<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Moyse Tutoring</title>
    <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Moyse Tutoring</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 13:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.moysetutoring.ca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Daphne</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/daphne/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/daphne/</guid>
      <description>1979 Thursday at 7pm is Daphne&amp;rsquo;s weekly hair appointment. She sits at &amp;ldquo;JoJons&amp;rdquo; examining the backs of her hands. She has to move her hands towards her face as she cannot move her head: Eileen is giving her blonde streaks this evening, so she must keep still. As Eileen pulls strands of hair through the rubber cap with a crochet hook, Daphne tries not to flinch, and focusses on her hands instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mazed</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/mazed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/mazed/</guid>
      <description>The girl in the red-and-white striped dress sits at the front of the class, right-hand side, opposite the blue door. Absorbed in her thoughts, she chews the end of her pencil.
❦ Her desk is next to a large locked cupboard, that holds teacher bits and pieces and extra reading books. Mrs. H&amp;mdash; is unnerving. Clearly, I have done something to annoy her, but I don&#39;t know what, but I am six years old, so adults are a mystery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lizzy</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/lizzy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/lizzy/</guid>
      <description>Lizzy&amp;rsquo;s heard it all before. Busy Lizzy. Frizzy Lizzy. Dizzy Lizzy&amp;hellip;and that&amp;rsquo;s just the nicknames. Having been born in the same year as Queen Elizabeth&amp;rsquo;s coronation, her name was an obvious choice, but she wishes that her parents had used a little more imagination when it came to christening their daughter. There had been two other Elizabeths in her class at primary school: Elizabeth, Lizzy and Bess. So that her teacher (Mrs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownie</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/brownie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/brownie/</guid>
      <description>It is Wednesday evening, and the eager Brownie Guide is making her way down the hill to the Baptist church hall.
❦ I quite like my Brownie uniform: brown dress, brown beret and yellow cross-over tie. I go on my own now, since my sisters have both progressed up to Guides. Besides, I am now seven, and perfectly capable of making the fifteen minute walk by myself. I&#39;m glad of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cats</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/cats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/cats/</guid>
      <description>The girl sits crosslegged on the classroom floor, listening to &amp;quot;Skimbleshanks the Railway Cat&amp;quot;. She twiddles her hair, bewitched by the clever, whimsical poem.
❦ Our classroom is outside the main school building. It is pre-fab, and probably not intended for long-term use; it seems to have decided to put down roots and take up permanent residence. There are two classrooms separated by a small hallway, where we can hang our coats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brenda (Mavis)</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/brenda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/brenda/</guid>
      <description>Brenda sits on the front pew of the crematorium. She&amp;rsquo;s glad that only her son and daughter-in-law can see her face. She sits, her back ram-rod straight, her hands in her lap, clutching the Order of Service and a balled up Kleenex. She is trying to focus on the words of the minister: &amp;ldquo;Forasmuch as it hath pleased Almighty God of his great mercy to take unto himself the soul of our dear brother here departed&amp;hellip;&amp;quot; She thinks, he wasn&amp;rsquo;t a dear brother and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure Almighty God will be at all pleased to find him rattling the bars of the pearly gates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aquarius</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/aquarius/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/aquarius/</guid>
      <description>The seven year-old girl in the grey pinafore dress is painting. With yellow and blue poster paints, sugar paper and cereal boxes, she is creating the backdrop for her seaside model.
❦ I&amp;rsquo;m sad to leave Mrs. S&amp;mdash;&amp;rsquo;s classroom. It has been a sanctuary for me: Mrs. S&amp;mdash; is sweet and kind; it&amp;rsquo;s like being taught by a favourite granny. She has white hair tied in a wispy bun and reading glasses on a chain, that she peers over to make sure we are paying attention to her as she reads us stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cathy</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/cathy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/cathy/</guid>
      <description>with apologies to Walter Benjamin Wivelsfield, Burgess Hill, Hassocks. Cathy notes the the names of the stations as they go past. Wivelsfield. What&amp;rsquo;s a Wivel? Is there a whole field of them? Or has the apostrophe been mislaid along the way and there is a field belonging to a Mr. Wivel on which the station was built? Perhaps a Mrs. Wivel cut the ribbon to open the ticket office. Wivelsfield, Burgess and Hassocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hastings</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/hastings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/hastings/</guid>
      <description>The girl with the milk-pale skin is paddling in the cold water of the English Channel, daydreaming.
❦ Our great aunt and uncle live in Hastings. We go and visit them every few months, and sometimes stay for a few days. Great Aunt Ruth has steel grey hair: no-nonsense pudding basin cut. Probably done with a pudding basin. She stoops as if she has dropped something in front of her, and shuffles in her sensible shoes from kitchen to dining room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arthur</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/arthur/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/arthur/</guid>
      <description>Boxing Day, 1973 Arthur sits at the end of his bed, tying his shoelaces. He is taking his time. He&amp;rsquo;s had a quiet morning listening to the radio and treating himself to a chapter or two of his new book: a thoughtful Christmas gift from his nephew - the life of Alexander the Great. But now, he must get himself ready to go over to his sister&amp;rsquo;s house for Boxing Day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gill</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/gill/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/gill/</guid>
      <description>Gill is making up the guest bed. She wishes she could be a bit more enthusiastic, put a little more heart into her task. No whistling while she works. Instead she is wrestling with the duvet cover. She has bought a new set especially for this visit: crisp white cotton from Marks and Spencer, washed carefully and ironed with extra care and attention, knowing that her visitor is very exacting about such matters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elizabeth</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/elizabeth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/elizabeth/</guid>
      <description>Elizabeth sits in the kitchen of her modest ground-floor flat. She sips her coffee and tries to read the morning paper, but the print wobbles and wavers. She can&#39;t focus. She wonders why she still has The Guardian delivered, since it&amp;rsquo;s all online these days. Habit, she supposes. There is something satisfying about going to the newsagent each week and paying her newspaper bill. She has had the same Saturday routine for as long as she can remember: brisk walk around the green, back via the newsagent and bakery for a weekend treat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alex</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/alex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/alex/</guid>
      <description>With thanks to Tarea Alex closes her laptop with a groan. Her Eng Lit 201 essay is just not coming together and it&amp;rsquo;s getting late. She should get herself home, but there is just time to drop into Scott&amp;rsquo;s Pantry for a cup of tea and a chip butty[1]. She is in need of comfort food, and nothing beats a chip butty on a damp autumn evening. It&amp;rsquo;s been a long shift at the university library and she is still no further forward with her research paper: Choose two characters from Shakespeare&#39;s tragedies and provide an argument on how they might represent his personal views on a topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shelter</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/shelter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/shelter/</guid>
      <description>The nine-year-old girl is sitting cross-legged on the parquet floor of the school hall, upset by the scenes of wretched housing in filthy streets. She wants someone to do something about it.
❦ The start of the new school year is heralded by the smell of varnish: the floor of the school hall is always resurfaced over the summer holidays, but it is scuffed and scratched within a week. I&amp;rsquo;m somewhat despondent about this, and wonder why a better varnish cannot be found so the shiny floor lasts longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arithmetic</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/arithmetic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/arithmetic/</guid>
      <description>The girl in the worn-out plimsols is posing for a photograph. She stands stiffly, gracelessly, trying to look serious and authentic. It is not working.
❦ I am in my second year in Mrs. R&amp;mdash;&amp;rsquo;s classroom and we are studying French. Our lessons are on scratchy 45rpm records; we listen carefully to the strange sounds and words, following along in our booklets. Mrs. R&amp;mdash; has a student teacher helping her this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Borders</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/borders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/borders/</guid>
      <description>The child with the allergy to all things feathered is sitting in the back of the car, thumb in her mouth and notebook on her lap, looking out for the sign for the border.
❦ Our two week holiday to Scotland every August starts in the same way. Everything is sorted and packed well in advance into our somewhat scruffy, somewhat tired suitcases. The fridge is cleared out and the door propped open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindness</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/kindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/kindness/</guid>
      <description>The girl with the bunch of purple heather sits on the side of the hill overlooking the loch, posing for a holiday memory.
❦ We leave Greenock to catch the ferry to Dunoon; mercifully, the crossing is short and the waves not too choppy, since, not only am I frequently car-sick, I am also prone to boat-sickness as well. This time around the sun is doing its best to peek around the skitty cotton-wool clouds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joe (Tom)</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/joe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/joe/</guid>
      <description>Joe is peeling potatoes. He fancies a bit of veggie pie for supper; he is working on some fine looking Maris Peers that he&amp;rsquo;s grown from a bag that he bought in his local supermarket. Growing potatoes seems like magic to Joe, and the whole process brings him pleasure. The shop-bought potatoes had sprouted nicely, sitting happily on the window sill in egg boxes. He still uses the tried-and-tested trench method his grandad showed him years ago, and this year&amp;rsquo;s crop has been excellent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kames</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/kames/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/kames/</guid>
      <description>The girl with the too-short hair cut makes her way down the dirt path. She is taking the short cut beside the football pitch; it peters out at the edge of the sea loch. She treads with care; her wooden Dr. Scholl&amp;rsquo;s sandals are not designed for this terrain and she is in danger of slipping. No matter. She can take her time since her uncle is still getting the little boat ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naja82</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/naja82/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/naja82/</guid>
      <description>With thanks to Yussanne Naja82 is bored. Two months into lockdown, and he&amp;rsquo;s feeling weary of the whole thing. It&amp;rsquo;s an odd range of emotions: on one side anxious about how this might all play out, but on the other fed up and - what did his dad call it? Scunnert. That&amp;rsquo;s it. Bored witless. On the bright side, he&amp;rsquo;s grateful he can work from home. Also on the bright side, his flat is above a coffee shop that is still open.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tom</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/tom/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/tom/</guid>
      <description>Swoosh. The train glides along the tracks, as if&amp;hellip;well, as if it is on rails. Tom finds the sound hard to describe in his mind. Swoosh is not quite right; more like a quiet tie fighter, perhaps. A tie fighter with laryngitis? He is bored. The mystery paperback he picked up at King&amp;rsquo;s Cross is not at all &amp;quot;A gripping mystery perfect for fans of Agatha Christie&amp;quot; as it was advertised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jack</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/jack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/jack/</guid>
      <description>Creative writing suggested by Stephen King Jack is bone weary. The past few weeks have been exhausting and he needs to take some time to think, to regroup somehow. The London traffic is treacle-slow: Saturday afternoon in Greenwich and the tourists are out in force. Gaggles of teenagers arm-in-arm making their way up the high street; groups of elderly Japanese, following their earnest guide who holds a yellow umbrella aloft and steers them towards the Cutty Sark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Princes</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/princes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/princes/</guid>
      <description>The asthmatic girl is climbing her way up the 287 steps of the Scott Monument in Edinburgh: her chest is tight and her lungs are straining, but she is determined to get to the top.
❦ We spend the day in Edinburgh, having stayed the night in a cosy guest house on Dalgleish Road. Mum refuses point blank to stay on caravan sites; the idea of camping or Butlin&amp;rsquo;s is an anathema to her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pat</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/pat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/pat/</guid>
      <description>with grateful thanks to Miss Brill Patricia is off on a little excursion. It is coming up to her birthday, and for a treat she is going to take afternoon tea at the Spa Hotel. It&amp;rsquo;s not often Patricia splashes out; after all, she must look after the pennies so that the pounds that make up her modest pension take care of themselves. Patricia (and it is Patricia, please note, not Pat, or Heaven forbid, Patty) lives frugally, ensuring that she stays within her grocery budget and making sure she keeps a check on the heating bill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wellington Road</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/wellingtonroad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/wellingtonroad/</guid>
      <description>Sunny 16 Wellington Road, April 2020 Henry is sulking. He sits in the corner with his head on his paws. As far as Sunny is concerned, Henry can sulk all he likes. &amp;ldquo;Henry, we are not going walkies. It is pouring with rain and you&amp;rsquo;ve been three times already today. You do not need to pee and it&amp;rsquo;s almost time for Belgravia, so stop giving me that sad puppy face.&amp;rdquo; Henry continues to give Sunny his best sad puppy face, but to no avail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peter</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/peter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/peter/</guid>
      <description>I met a traveller from an antique land,
Who said&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;Two vast and trunkless legs of stone
Stand in the desert. . . . Near them, on the sand,
Half sunk a shattered visage lies, whose frown,
And wrinkled lip, and sneer of cold command,
Tell that its sculptor well those passions read
Which yet survive, stamped on these lifeless things,
The hand that mocked them, and the heart that fed;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ben</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/ben/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/ben/</guid>
      <description>Ben sits in his father&amp;rsquo;s study, leafing through a huge ring binder. It must be three inches thick, full of letters and documents that go back ten years. His father&amp;rsquo;s funeral is tomorrow, so he is spending the day sorting through his father&amp;rsquo;s belongings. Ben is the trustee of David&amp;rsquo;s estate, and although he is getting support and guidance from his Uncle Peter, he is finding the whole process both and daunting and depressing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronald</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/ronald/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/ronald/</guid>
      <description>1931 Ronald looks at his watch. 12.30. His next tutorial session is not until 3pm, so he has time for a leisurely lunch. He is not looking forward to his afternoon appointment with Chadwick: his student&amp;rsquo;s PhD thesis, that is loosely entitled &amp;ldquo;The Monsters and Beowulf&amp;rdquo;, is dull and uninspired. Even the title is hackneyed. Ronald finds it hard to focus as Chadwick tries to justify his proposal, but Chadwick&amp;rsquo;s flat voice and pedestrian thinking drains Ronald of any enthusiasm, so his blathering goes in one ear and swiftly out of the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duncan</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/duncan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/duncan/</guid>
      <description>Duncan is taking his lunch break. He checks in with Cathy, the supermarket manager: &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s me on lunch, now.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Right you are, Duncan.&amp;rdquo; He hangs his apron on his peg in the staff room and takes his wind-cheater. It&amp;rsquo;s a fine June day, but there&amp;rsquo;s still a stiff breeze coming off the river. He takes a little detour, going down the steps towards the esplanade. He has his fish paste sandwiches stuffed in one pocket and a scruffy paperback in the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kay</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/kay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/kay/</guid>
      <description>1985 Kay is on the plane to Malaga. She is on her second mini bottle of Teacher&amp;rsquo;s scotch, knocking back the first one in two gulps, just to steady her nerves. The second one is lasting a bit longer, now that she has relaxed a bit. Plus, she has realised that the plane is not going to drop from the sky like a stone, and the pilot seems to know what he/she is doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lassie</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/lassie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/lassie/</guid>
      <description>a nonsense story for Andy Lassie is dog-tired. But, being a dog (specifically a collie) that&amp;rsquo;s not unexpected. She&amp;rsquo;s worn out from an afternoon of herding sheep. Specifically, black-faced sheep. She lopes along next to Mr and Mrs McTavish and their son, Joe. No-one speaks, as no-one (including Lassie) has the energy to converse, be it in words, growls or barks. Lassie&amp;rsquo;s tail is jammed between her legs, and her sable coat is splashed with peaty rain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/john/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/john/</guid>
      <description>John is off on a jaunt. It&amp;rsquo;s a fair April day, and he fancies a trip to the seaside. He&amp;rsquo;s partial to Whitby with its eccentricities and weird history. The drive should take around an hour, but he&amp;rsquo;s planning to stop along the way. Take his time. Savour the landscape. Enjoy a bit of sea air.
Retirement suits John well. He&amp;rsquo;s made a bit of money, a nest-egg so to speak, and has few financial concerns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/david/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/david/</guid>
      <description>For David. Rest in Peace. David is raking up the leaves. It&amp;rsquo;s an hour before school starts, but he likes to get a jump start. It won&amp;rsquo;t be long before there are hundreds of teenagers making their way down this path into school. He has a leaf blower but he prefers to do this work by hand: raking the leaves into piles and stuffing them into large paper sacks to be added to the compost heap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andrew</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/andrew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/andrew/</guid>
      <description>Monday night.
Andrew is struggling to get to sleep. He&amp;rsquo;s tried sleeping on his side but he can&amp;rsquo;t get comfortable. He flips his pillow over for the third time and turns on to his back. His feet are too cold. He wonders if he can be bothered to go and find a pair of socks. His pillow has the consistency of a house brick so he pummels it a couple of times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alison</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/alison/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/alison/</guid>
      <description>20th March 2020
Alison sits at her kitchen table with her second glass of Zinfandel. It&amp;rsquo;s not a particularly good one, but frankly, she does not care. It will do. She takes a gulp (ugh - mouthwash!) and tries to take in the situation. Lockdown. Shelter at home. It feels like a chapter from a badly-written dystopian novel. This is not at all what she was expecting. Not at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ginny (May)</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/ginny/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/ginny/</guid>
      <description>(May) Ginny is trotting down to the beach to have a swim. It&amp;rsquo;s a warmish July day; a few clouds in the sky and a distinct possibly of rain later, so she is making a dash for it before the drizzle begins. It&amp;rsquo;s been a bewildering few days and she needs to clear her head. Swimming will be just the thing: a few laps back and forth while the sea is not too choppy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laura</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/laura/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/laura/</guid>
      <description>Laura is on her way to work in her trusty VW Golf. It&amp;rsquo;s got a few dents and scratches, and is rusty here and there, but she doesn&amp;rsquo;t care. It starts first time, does great miles to the gallon and is easy to park. She&amp;rsquo;s got the radio on, and is singing along to a chirpy pop song, not thinking too much about the day ahead. She works for the UK subsidy of a US company; most of her job is thinking up new marketing ideas and keeping track of sales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baggage</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/baggage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/baggage/</guid>
      <description>History and all that clan malarky.
You can take it or leave it.
I&#39;d rather leave it if you don&#39;t mind.
Too cumbersome to carry about,
like having to manoeuvre a four-tier wedding cake
whilst running for the bus in sky-high stilettos.
Like wearing lip-gloss in a howling gale,
it just gets irritating and awkward.
Having to remember this and ponder on that,
and try to work out who&#39;s who and who&#39;s not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synaesthesia</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/syn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/syn/</guid>
      <description>Vision is always synaesthetic.
Impure, permeable, blurry.
Other senses come creeping in,
unwelcome and bad-tempered,
not wiping their feet and demanding cups of tea.
Ear-plugs don&#39;t work.
Sounds wiggle their way around the latex
to remind you of what was said,
what music was playing.
A taste forms in your mouth.
Is that coffee? Caramel perhaps.
It&#39;s on the tip of your tongue.
Perhaps it isn&#39;t a taste at all.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
