<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Moyse Tutoring</title>
    <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Moyse Tutoring</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 13:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mazed</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/mazed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/mazed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The girl in the red-and-white striped dress sits at the front of the class, right-hand side,
opposite the blue door. Absorbed in her thoughts, she chews the end of her pencil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownie</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/brownie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/brownie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is Wednesday evening, and the eager Brownie Guide is making her way down the hill to the Baptist
church hall.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cats</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/cats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/cats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The girl sits crosslegged on the classroom floor, listening to “Skimbleshanks the Railway Cat”. She
twiddles her hair, bewitched by the clever, whimsical poem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aquarius</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/aquarius/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/aquarius/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The seven year-old girl in the grey pinafore dress is painting. With yellow and blue poster paints,
sugar paper and cereal boxes, she is creating the backdrop for her seaside model.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hastings</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/hastings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/hastings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The girl with the milk-pale skin is paddling in the cold water of the English Channel,
daydreaming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shelter</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/shelter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/shelter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The nine-year-old girl is sitting cross-legged on the parquet floor of the school hall, upset by the
scenes of wretched housing in filthy streets. She wants someone to do something about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arithmetic</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/arithmetic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/arithmetic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The girl in the worn-out plimsols is posing for a photograph. She stands stiffly, gracelessly,
trying to look serious and authentic. It is not working.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Borders</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/borders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/borders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The child with the allergy to all things feathered is sitting in the back of the car, thumb in her
mouth and notebook on her lap, looking out for the sign for the border.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindness</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/kindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/kindness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The girl with the bunch of purple heather sits on the side of the hill overlooking the loch, posing
for a holiday memory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kames</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/kames/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/kames/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The girl with the too-short hair cut makes her way down the dirt path. She is taking the short cut
beside the football pitch; it peters out at the edge of the sea loch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Princes</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/princes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/princes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The asthmatic girl is climbing her way up the 287 steps of the Scott Monument in Edinburgh: her
chest is tight and her lungs are straining, but she is determined to get to the top.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pat</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/pat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/pat/</guid>
      <description>With grateful thanks to Miss Brill.
Patricia is off on a little excursion. It is coming up to her birthday, and for a treat she is going to take afternoon tea at the Spa Hotel. It’s not often Patricia splashes out; after all, she must look after the pennies so that the pounds that make up her modest pension take care of themselves. Patricia (and it is Patricia, please note, not Pat, or Heaven forbid, Patty) lives frugally, ensuring that she stays within her grocery budget and making sure she keeps a check on the heating bill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronald</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/ronald/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/ronald/</guid>
      <description>1931
Ronald looks at his watch. 12.30. His next tutorial session is not until 3pm, so he has time for a leisurely lunch. He is not looking forward to his afternoon appointment with Chadwick: his student’s PhD thesis, that is loosely entitled “The Monsters and Beowulf”, is dull and uninspired. Even the title is hackneyed. Ronald finds it hard to focus as Chadwick earnestly tries to justify his proposal, but Chadwick’s flat voice and pedestrian thinking drains Ronald of any enthusiasm and his blathering goes in one ear and swiftly out of the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brenda (Mavis)</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/brenda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/brenda/</guid>
      <description>Brenda sits on the front pew of the crematorium. She’s glad that only her son and daughter-in-law can see her face. She sits, her back ram-rod straight, with her hands in her lap, clutching the Order of Service and a balled up Kleenex. She is trying to focus on the words of the minister: “Forasmuch as it hath pleased Almighty God of his great mercy to take unto himself the soul of our dear brother here departed…” She thinks, he wasn’t a dear brother and I’m not sure Almighty God will be at all pleased to find him rattling the bars of the pearly gates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lizzy</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/lizzy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/lizzy/</guid>
      <description>Lizzy’s heard it all before. Busy Lizzy. Frizzy Lizzy. Dizzy Lizzy… and that’s just the nicknames. Having been born in the same year as Queen Elizabeth’s coronation, her name was an obvious choice, but she wishes that her parents had used a little more imagination when it came to christening their daughter. There had been two other Elizabeths in her class at primary school: Elizabeth, Lizzy and Bess. So that her teacher (Mrs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daphne</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/daphne/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/daphne/</guid>
      <description>1979
Thursday at 7pm is Daphne’s weekly hair appointment. She sits at “JoJons” examining the backs of her hands. She has to move her hands towards her face as she cannot move her head: Eileen is giving her blonde streaks this evening, so she must keep still. As Eileen pulls strands of hair through the rubber cap with a crochet hook, Daphne tries not to flinch, and focusses on her hands instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duncan</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/duncan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/duncan/</guid>
      <description>Duncan is taking his lunch break. He checks in with Cathy, the supermarket manager: “That’s me on lunch, now.” “Right you are, Duncan.” He hangs his apron on his peg in the staff room and takes his wind-cheater. It’s a fine June day, but there’s still a stiff breeze coming off the river. He takes a little detour, going down the steps towards the esplanade. He has his fish paste sandwiches stuffed in one pocket and a scruffy paperback in the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lassie</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/lassie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/lassie/</guid>
      <description>A nonsense story for Andy.
Lassie is dog-tired. But, being a dog (specifically a collie) that’s not unexpected. She’s worn out from an afternoon of herding sheep. Specifically, black-faced sheep. She lopes along next to Mr and Mrs McTavish and their son, Joe. No-one speaks, as no-one (including Lassie) has the energy to converse, be it in words, growls or barks. Lassie’s tail is jammed between her legs, and her sable coat is splashed with peaty rain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peter</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/peter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/peter/</guid>
      <description>I met a traveller from an antique land,
Who said &amp;mdash; “Two vast and trunkless legs of stone
Stand in the desert... Near them, on the sand,
Half sunk a shattered visage lies, whose frown,
And wrinkled lip, and sneer of cold command,
Tell that its sculptor well those passions read
Which yet survive, stamped on these lifeless things,
The hand that mocked them, and the heart that fed;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cathy</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/cathy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/cathy/</guid>
      <description>With apologies to Walter Benjamin
Wivelsfield, Burgess Hill, Hassocks. Cathy notes the the names of the stations as they go past. Wivelsfield. What’s a Wivel? Is there a whole field of them? Or has the apostrophe been mislaid along the way and there is a field belonging to a Mr. Wivel on which the station was built? Perhaps a Mrs. Wivel cut the ribbon to open the ticket office. Wivelsfield, Burgess and Hassocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tom</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/tom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/tom/</guid>
      <description>Tom thinks about childhood holidays.
Swoosh. The train glides along the tracks, as if is on&amp;hellip; well, rails. Tom finds the sound hard to describe in his mind. Swoosh is not quite right; more like a quiet tie fighter, perhaps. A tie fighter with laryngitis? He is bored. The mystery paperback he picked up at King’s Cross is not at all “A gripping mystery perfect for fans of Agatha Christie” as it was advertised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fur Coat</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/fur-coat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/fur-coat/</guid>
      <description>Big man, beaming toothless.
Lurching lumpily onto the bus,
Bags crunching and rattling
With cans and bottles,
Pleased with his meagre treasure
Takes up the whole back seat,
Chatting away to himself.
Old man, withered and worn,
Scrawny legs crossed on the bus
Squirming uncomfortably
Spluttering and coughing
He has no handkerchief;
Glutinous spit propelled
With every heave of his lungs.
Young man, unsteady on his feet,
Clambers doggedly onto the bus</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baggage</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/baggage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/baggage/</guid>
      <description>History and all that clan malarky.
You can take it or leave it.
I&amp;rsquo;d rather leave it if you don&amp;rsquo;t mind.
Too cumbersome to carry about,
like having to manoeuvre a four-tier wedding cake
whilst running for the bus in sky-high stilettos.
Like wearing lip-gloss in a howling gale,
it just gets irritating and awkward.
Having to remember this and ponder on that,
and try to work out who&amp;rsquo;s who and who&amp;rsquo;s not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synaesthesia</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/syn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/syn/</guid>
      <description>Vision is always synaesthetic.
Impure, permeable, blurry.
Other senses come creeping in,
unwelcome and bad-tempered,
not wiping their feet and demanding cups of tea.
Ear-plugs don’t work.
Sounds wiggle their way around the latex
to remind you of what was said,
what music was playing.
A taste forms in your mouth.
Is that coffee? Caramel perhaps.
It’s on the tip of your tongue.
Perhaps it isn’t a taste at all.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>