<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Moyse Tutoring</title>
    <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Moyse Tutoring</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 11:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Kames</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/kames/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/kames/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The girl with the too-short hair cut makes her way down the dirt path. She is taking the short cut
beside the football pitch; it peters out at the edge of the sea loch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tread with care; my wooden Dr. Scholl’s sandals are not designed for this terrain and I am in
danger of slipping. No matter. I can take my time since “uncle” L&amp;mdash; is still getting the little
boat ready. There is a cool, salty breeze coming from the loch, but I’m warm in my Aran jumper. My
mum made it specially for me; it has two rows of bobbly knots down the front that I twiddle with. My
shorts are still too big for me: hand-me-downs from my older sister that I have not quite grown
into. I reach the bottom of the slope without too much difficulty and stop to inspect my leg. There
are two pinky-red cloth plasters: one just inside my knee, and one on the outside of my ankle. They
are itchy, as are the dozen or so scratches that run down my leg from knee to foot. Stuffing my
thumb in my mouth, I count them slowly. There are fourteen, including the smaller ones. I continue
on my way over the rocky beach towards the water, still happily sucking my thumb. No-one is
watching, so I will not get the usual telling-off. “Only babies suck their thumbs,” my mother
scolds. At the water’s edge I put my toes into the water, testing it out. Too cold for swimming, but
good for paddling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further along I reach the mouth of the stream that runs beside our uncle’s cottage. here I have
spent gleeful hours exploring the narrow braided channels and miniature waterfalls. I like the
cottage with its wobbly salt-scraped wooden floors and ancient hair-stuffed sofa bed. I like washing
in the soft cold water. I like rifling through “auntie” N&amp;mdash;’s draws: among the hair grips and
packets of Rennies I have found real treasure: a bottle of magical fake tan and a Max Factor
lipstick. The cottage has an outside toilet with a corrugated iron roof: torches hang in the
entrance way ready for night-time trips to the loo. We have been staying here for a few days: mum,
dad and my older sister. I like my uncle. He’s funny and kind, and likes making up little songs as
he potters about. Today’s song is about finding the equipment for fishing: “Ting-a-ling a-ling
a-ling, I’ve lost the ball of string…”, he trills. Mum and dad are not coming on the fishing trip:
mum feels guilty about not paying for the cottage (she is always embarrassed by anything that seems
like charity), and so I will be weeding the garden as payment. Dad is whitewashing the outside loo;
perhaps he feels guilty, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am interrupted by my sister who comes sashaying down to the beach. I wish I could sashay, too, but
my movements are awkward and lumpen. We share the sofa bed at night with its buttercup yellow sheets
and scratchy pale woollen blankets. The cottage backs on to a rookery; at summer dusk the birds make
it difficult to get to sleep with their constant cawing and screeching. Last year, we scared
ourselves half to death: we watched “The Birds” on the cottage’s old black-and-white television, and
then huddled under the bed covers, terrified of the noise outside. My sister wants to know when the
boat will be ready, but I don’t know. There is something wrong with the outboard motor and Uncle
L&amp;mdash; is trying to fix it. While we wait, I take an amble among the rocks looking for
shells. Meantime, my sister grumpily throws pebbles into the loch, as if they had done something to
irritate her. The boat is ready, and the we head towards our uncle who is calling to us; my sister
marches in front with me trailing behind. We clamber in, and sit opposite each other on the bow. Our
Uncle L&amp;mdash; is at the stern, steering us through the shadowy water. I watch my sister under my
fringe. I cannot quite trust her; the barbed-wire fence has taught me as much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driving to the cottage we had both needed to wee, but since we were nowhere near a public
convenience, Dad had to stop at the side of the road. A barbed-wire fence was between us and the
bushes that would give some privacy, but we were both so desperate after the cherry colas at lunch
time, we had little choice. My sister had gone first, and I had followed, gingerly climbing over the
fence. On the way back, my sister was faster and more nimble, and, worried that I would be told off
for making my parents wait, I rushed my descent and slipped. The rusty barbs caught my right
leg. Straight away, I knew there would be trouble. My parents had to take me to the nearest hospital
for treatment; the bleeding stopped on the way, but the wounds needed cleaning and I would require a
tetanus injection. I apologised all the way there. The motherly nurse had been soothing and
re-assuring, but I knew it was all my fault. The throbbing pain of the injection in my arm that
night had seemed a kind of penance: what I had deserved for my clumsiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;max-width:30em;&#34; src=&#34;http://www.moysetutoring.ca/images/0023.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Boat Picture&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;L&amp;mdash; cuts the motor, and the boat bobs for a time on the quiet surface. He sets a fishing line, and
lets it out behind the boat. It barely makes a shimmer in the water as we move off, heading south
towards the wide open inlet. Far too quickly, the line is being twisted and there is quick movement
in the water. L&amp;mdash; shuts the engine, and carefully draws in the line. Three mackerel have been
caught, their zebra backs iridescent as they are lifted out of the water. I can’t watch as he
swiftly hits their heads against the bottom of the boat. Supper has been supplied, but I will refuse
to eat it. I am sorry for the fish as they look up at me, surprised by their fate. I look out
towards the inlet, miserable. I am alarmed to see the weather up ahead: storm clouds are moving
quickly towards us, black and forbidding. Almost immediately, it starts to rain and Uncle L&amp;mdash; turns
the boat around, his face grim and rigid. He says nothing as the storm bears down on the loch. The
rain is coming down in sheets and my sister and I exchange frightened glances, but do not speak,
willing the little boat to the shore. As we near the rocky beach, L&amp;mdash; jumps out and pulls the boat
up to safety. We scramble out onto the rocks and run as fast as our legs will carry us up the slope
to the cottage. We arrive back, our Aaran jumpers soaked through. Mum instructs us girls to strip
off our sodden clothes and we dry ourselves on scratchy blue towels. Dad and Uncle L&amp;mdash; chat together
in the living room, watching the rain blurring the view of the loch. The storm passes over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The woman with the long curly hair makes her way down to the beach. Along the strand line,
purposeful and ponderous, she searches for sea glass.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mazed</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/mazed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/mazed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The girl in the red-and-white striped dress sits at the front of the class, right-hand side,
opposite the  blue door.  Absorbed in her thoughts, she chews the end of her pencil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her desk is next to a large locked cupboard, that holds extra textbooks and teacher bits and
pieces. Mrs. Hardy is unnerving. Clearly, I have done something to annoy her, but I don’t know what,
but I am six years old, so adults are a bit of a mystery.  Her mouth makes an ugly turn down when
she speaks to me. I know I have erred in some way, but I have not been informed of my mistake, and
cannot put it right. Mrs. Hardy has favourites. Sadly, I am not in this happy band; I resent the
ones who are petted and praised. I am not approved of, I am not gathered into her wiry, red-woollen
arms. I sit on my own at a desk for two until Victoria Parvin joins our class. She’s casually
spiteful, and throws my pack of class coloured pencils behind the teacher’s cupboard. I have no idea
what to do. I am rendered mute, immobile. I cannot think of the words to explain what has happened,
and I don’t know how to get my pencils back. I do my best to explain my predicament to Mrs. Hardy,
but my account does not make any sense to her and she dismisses me with a flick of her wrist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numbers and words scrape and scratch their way across the blackboard in dusty chalk, but I can make
little sense of them. I beaver away in my exercise book: the cover is blue; the top half of page
plain for drawing, bottom half lined for writing. The ends of my pencils are chewed to shreds from
my bite marks. I want my work to look neat and tidy, but all to often my writing wanders around the
page like a cow in a field, and the corners are dog-eared and tatty. I try to smooth them down, but
they keep curling back up. I do my best to write my “news”, but I have little imagination and am
impaired by the anxiety that takes up half of my thinking; it seems parts of my brain are filled
with fluff, or perhaps it is just stuck, as if the cogs haven’t had enough oil and are jammed,
stuttering and faltering. I’ve added a new tactic to help appease the constant drip-drip of fear in
my thoughts: chewing tiny holes in my pinafore skirt. I nibble whilst no-one is looking, the
nip-snip of the threads between my teeth is somehow comforting. My mother thinks we have moths, and
I have managed to persuade her that this is the correct analysis. I’m pleased with my small victory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mother provides me with homemade clothes for school: the regulation red-and-white striped summer
dresses are created at the dining room table with an old Singer machine. Mum likes to make us
matching Victorian bloomers using the same material. She believes them to be charming, but I’m
humiliated, and want to have normal knickers from Marks and Spencer like everyone else. We have
regulation navy knickers and white vests for PE: one week I forget to bring mine, and have to do PE
in my ridiculous bloomers. I hike them up as best I can, but they, of course, get attention, and I
blush and squirm my way through 30 dreadful minutes of pretending to be a tree in the wind and a
bird hopping between branches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The school year goes past in a colourless monotony. Days are tediously predictable:
assembly-class-break-class-dinner-class-home. I like school lunches. We have good-natured dinner
ladies, who prepare tasty meals. I especially like the lady who serves the salad. “Beetroot?” she
always asks. Lunch breaks are made easier by my sweet friend, Janet, who is from another form. We
spend our time performing pretend weather forecasts in front of a blue door, where the paint has
peeled to roughly the shape of the British Isles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at my desk, I have little to write in my “news” book: our Monday afternoon exercise, in which
we write about our week. I chew the end of my pencil and consider my options. Little flakes of
yellow paint come off and get stuck to my tongue; I spit them out into my white cotton hanky, trying
not to draw Mrs. Hardy’s scrutiny. Our books are collected at the end of class by a book monitor: an
accolade I can never reach. It is an honour only bestowed on one of Mrs. Hardy’s
favourites. However, towards the end of the year I finally have something interesting to write for
my “news” book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;max-width:30em;&#34; src=&#34;http://www.moysetutoring.ca/images/IMG_0489_edit.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pebbles Picture&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had been a average day at St.Leonards-on-Sea, home to my great aunt and uncle.  We had driven
down in the white Austin 1100: Mum and dog in the passenger seat, Dad, of course, driving, three
sisters on the back seat with the picnic basket and thermos flasks tucked under our feet. We parked
on the Marina, near to the Warrior Square gardens, and made our way down to the beach with all our
paraphernalia. Decked out a hand-me-down swimsuit and towelling tabards, I played on the pebbly
beach most of the day, doing my best to avoid the tar from a recent oil spill. Inevitably I got
blobs of the sticky black goop on my flip-flops and towel, malevolent treacle that I had to clean
off later with a special solution. We paddled and splashed around the stone groynes; we were all
strong swimmers. Even if my English composition was lacklustre, at least I could do two widths
breaststroke. I had the green patch sewn on to my swimming costume to prove it. Somehow, suddenly,
both of my sisters managed swim over the top of groyne and fall in the other side, where the water
was much deeper. Although they could have swum back, they panicked, and my dad had to rescue them
both. It was all over in a moment. Watching from the water’s edge, I had been astounded by how
quickly this was over and done. I stood with my mouth open, reflecting later to my sisters that I
was “amazed.” My mother mis-heard this, and, as she related the story to friends and family, she
quoted me as saying, “I was mazed.” I said nothing of the sort, but grinned along, since it got me
attention for being cute - a novelty for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try this new trick with Mrs. Hardy, hoping it will elicit the same affectionate smiles. Carefully,
I draw the incident with stick figures and crayons, and write a few sentences, ending with, “I was
mazed.” I hope that this will mean that Mrs. Hardy will look on me more kindly, and give me one of
her coveted gold starts, but I am mistaken. My exercise book comes back, corrected, with a red biro
“a” in front of the “mazed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The woman in the striped linen dress sits at the front of the class, carefully, deliberately editing
her student’s essay.  Absorbed in her thoughts, she chews the end of her red pen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baggage</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/baggage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/baggage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;History and all that clan malarky.&lt;br /&gt;
You can take it or leave it.&lt;br /&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;d rather leave it if you don&amp;rsquo;t mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too cumbersome to carry about,&lt;br /&gt;
like having to manoeuvre a four-tier wedding cake&lt;br /&gt;
whilst running for the bus in sky-high stilettos.&lt;br /&gt;
Like wearing lip-gloss in a howling gale,&lt;br /&gt;
it just gets irritating and awkward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having to remember this and ponder on that,&lt;br /&gt;
and try to work out who&amp;rsquo;s who and who&amp;rsquo;s not.&lt;br /&gt;
Who’s kith and who is kin, and what our forebears bore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best to leave that kind of baggage neatly stored&lt;br /&gt;
in a hat box on the top shelf of the cupboard,&lt;br /&gt;
or under the bed, or in the basement&lt;br /&gt;
where it can argue with itself and collect dust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I&amp;rsquo;m kicking off those glittery Louboutins&lt;br /&gt;
and hailing a taxi. Barefoot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;max-width:30em;&#34; src=&#34;http://www.moysetutoring.ca/images/Pepper-Family.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pepper Family Picture&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synaesthesia</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/syn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/syn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vision is always synaesthetic.&lt;br /&gt;
Impure, permeable, blurry.&lt;br /&gt;
Other senses come creeping in,&lt;br /&gt;
unwelcome and bad-tempered,&lt;br /&gt;
not wiping their feet and demanding cups of tea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ear-plugs don’t work.&lt;br /&gt;
Sounds wiggle their way around the latex&lt;br /&gt;
to remind you of what was said,&lt;br /&gt;
what music was playing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A taste forms in your mouth.&lt;br /&gt;
Is that coffee? Caramel perhaps.&lt;br /&gt;
It’s on the tip of your tongue.&lt;br /&gt;
Perhaps it isn’t a taste at all.&lt;br /&gt;
The scent of something you can’t quite remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, there is a scratching at the back of your neck.&lt;br /&gt;
It’s not the label; you cut that out.&lt;br /&gt;
It’s persistent and uncomfortable and rolling your shoulders doesn’t shift it.&lt;br /&gt;
It’s a reminder: defining the object is tricky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;max-width:30em;&#34; src=&#34;http://www.moysetutoring.ca/images/IMG_0460.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lavender Picture&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fur Coat</title>
      <link>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/fur-coat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.moysetutoring.ca/post/fur-coat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Big man, beaming toothless.&lt;br /&gt;
Lurching lumpily onto the bus,&lt;br /&gt;
Bags crunching and rattling&lt;br /&gt;
With cans and bottles,&lt;br /&gt;
Pleased with his meagre treasure&lt;br /&gt;
Takes up the whole back seat,&lt;br /&gt;
Chatting away to himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old man, withered and worn,&lt;br /&gt;
Scrawny legs crossed on the bus&lt;br /&gt;
Squirming uncomfortably&lt;br /&gt;
Spluttering and coughing&lt;br /&gt;
He has no handkerchief;&lt;br /&gt;
Glutinous spit propelled&lt;br /&gt;
With every heave of his lungs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Young man, unsteady on his feet,&lt;br /&gt;
Clambers doggedly onto the bus&lt;br /&gt;
Cumbersome body wedged in.&lt;br /&gt;
Chuckles shamelessly&lt;br /&gt;
Hands pressing on his knees,&lt;br /&gt;
Straining against the nervous tic&lt;br /&gt;
That ripples through him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fur coat and no knickers, this town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;max-width:30em;&#34; src=&#34;http://www.moysetutoring.ca/images/IMG_2666.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rainy Vancouver Picture&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>